<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle>
    <!- SKIPPED DATA ->
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <!- SKIPPED DATA ->
            <ArticleTitle>Cell Walls and the Convergent Evolution of the Viral Envelope.</ArticleTitle>
            <!- SKIPPED DATA ->
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>Why some viruses are enveloped while others lack an outer lipid bilayer is a major question in viral evolution but one that has received relatively little attention. The viral envelope serves several functions, including protecting the RNA or DNA molecule(s), evading recognition by the immune system, and facilitating virus entry. Despite these commonalities, viral envelopes come in a wide variety of shapes and configurations. The evolution of the viral envelope is made more puzzling by the fact that nonenveloped viruses are able to infect a diverse range of hosts across the tree of life. We reviewed the entry, transmission, and exit pathways of all (101) viral families on the 2013 International Committee on Taxonomy of Viruses (ICTV) list. By doing this, we revealed a strong association between the lack of a viral envelope and the presence of a cell wall in the hosts these viruses infect. We were able to propose a new hypothesis for the existence of enveloped and nonenveloped viruses, in which the latter represent an adaptation to cells surrounded by a cell wall, while the former are an adaptation to animal cells where cell walls are absent. In particular, cell walls inhibit viral entry and exit, as well as viral transport within an organism, all of which are critical waypoints for successful infection and spread. Finally, we discuss how this new model for the origin of the viral envelope impacts our overall understanding of virus evolution. </AbstractText>
                <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2015, American Society for Microbiology. All Rights Reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Buchmann</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Jan P</ForeName>
                    <Initials>JP</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Marie Bashir Institute for Infectious Diseases and Biosecurity, Charles Perkins Centre, School of Biological Sciences, and Sydney Medical School, The University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Holmes</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Edward C</ForeName>
                    <Initials>EC</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Marie Bashir Institute for Infectious Diseases and Biosecurity, Charles Perkins Centre, School of Biological Sciences, and Sydney Medical School, The University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia edward.holmes@sydney.edu.au.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <!- SKIPPED DATA ->
        </Article>
        <!- SKIPPED DATA ->
        <ReferenceList>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Nature. 2014 Jan 16;505(7483):432-5</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24336205</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Crit Rev Microbiol. 1988;15(4):339-89</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3060317</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <!- SKIPPED DATA ->
        </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

</PubmedArticleSet>
